Guide to the Pare Lorentz papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VII: U.S. Army Air Forces, 1941-1947
  During World War II, Lorentz directed the Overseas Technical Unit, which was detailed to gather footage to help American pilots spot landmarks and airstrips around the world. This series has maps, correspondence, journals, and photographs. It also contains scripts from several of the briefing films that were produced as guides for different routes. Large format Air Corps photos depict Africa, Iran, Arabia, India, Morocco, Egypt, Libya, Iceland, Labrador, England, and Scotland. Others are in France or unidentified.
  - Maps, 1943-1945 (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - Stills, 1943-1945, (10 Folders) (Box 128, Folder 2 to 11)
  - Reports, 1944-1945 (Box 128, Folder 12)
  - Lloyd Nosler, 1942-1943 (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - Production No. 5 "Back of the Yards," 1947 (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - Personal and OTU Commendations, 1943-1945 (Box 129, Folder 3)
  - Personnel Records, 1945 (Box 129, Folder 4)
  - OTU - Air Transport Command Motion Picture Section, 1945 (Box 129, Folder 5)
  - Pare Lorentz Duty Record, 1942-1945 (Box 129, Folder 6)
  - OTU Air Transport Command, 1943-1945, (2 Folders) (Box 129, Folder 7 to 8)
  - Activities Reports, 1945 (Box 129, Folder 9)
  - Briefing Scripts, 1944-1945, (6 Folders) (Box 130, Folder 1 to 6)
  - Briefing Scripts, 1944-1945, (3 Folders) (Box 131, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Consolidated Report of Shipments, January-May 1945, (5 Folders) (Box 131, Folder 4 to 8)
  - Consolidated Report of Shipments, June-November 1945, (6 Folders) (Box 132, Folder 1 to 6)
  - Pathé News Feature Orders for O.T.U Script of Movie, 1945 (Box 132, Folder 7)
  - Consolidated Report of Shipments, April-December 1944, (8 Folders) (Box 132, Folder 8 to 16)
  - Clippings, 1945 (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - Maps, 1940s (Box 133, Folder 2)
  - Daily Journal, March 1943-June 1944, (4 Folders) (Box 133, Folder 3 to 6)
  - Daily Journal, July 1944-September 1945, (5 Folders) (Box 134, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Daily Journal, October 1945-January 1946 (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - Catalogue of Still Picture Captions Mission No. 5, 1944 (Box 135, Folder 2)
  - Book of photos, 1944-1945 (Box 135, Folder 3)
  - Secret History of "Snowball," 1944 (Box 135, Folder 4)
  - 4-A. China, 1944-1945 (Box 135, Folder 5)
  - ATC--General, 1944-1945 (Box 135, Folder 6)
  - Historical Section, 1944-1945 (Box 135, Folder 7)
  - Pan Am, 1944-1945 (Box 136, Folder 1)
  - 3. Europe, 1944-1945 (Box 136, Folder 2)
  - Progress of War, 1944-1945 (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - 4-B. Pacific Ocean, 1944-1945 (Box 136, Folder 4)
  - Maps: ATC Official, 1944-1945 (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - Magazine Material, 1944-1945 (Box 136, Folder 6)
  - Personal Narratives, 1941-1942 (Box 136, Folder 7)
  - Prewar Aviation, 1944-1945 (Box 136, Folder 8)
  - ATC Pilot Training Films List, 1944-1945 (Box 136, Folder 9)
  - Air Transport Command, 1944-1945 (Box 136, Folder 10)
  - Research Notes And Reports, 1944-1945 (Box 136, Folder 11)
  - ATC Research Material, 1944-1945 (Box 136, Folder 12)
  - History--Overseas Technical Unit, 1944-1945 (Box 136, Folder 13)
  - Summary of Operations of the Air Transport Command, 1944-1945 (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - ICAO Regional Manual--North Atlantic, 1944-1945 (Box 137, Folder 2)
  - Pare Lorentz--Personal File, 1943-1945, (2 Folders) (Box 137, Folder 3 to 4)
  - History of the Air Corps Ferrying Command, 1944-1945 (Box 137, Folder 5)
  - Overseas Technical Unit Historical Research, 1944-1945 (Box 138, Folder 1)
  - ATC Stills, 1944-1945 (Box 138, Folder 2)
  - ATC Files, 1944-1945 (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - Weather and Radio, 1944-1945 (Box 138, Folder 4)
  - History of the Ferrying Command, 1941-1942 (Box 139, Folder 1)
  - Publicity Materials, 1944-1945 (Box 139, Folder 2)
  - Special Orders, 1944-1945 (Box 139, Folder 3)
  - Consolidated Report of Shipments, 1945 (Box 139, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 139, Folder 5)
  - Consolidated Activities Report, 1945 (Box 139, Folder 6)
  - Mission Maps, 1944-1945 (Box 139, Folder 7)
  - War Department Films, 1947 (Box 140)
    - "Back of the Yards," 1947 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - Film Memo, 1947 (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - Cleveland Trip, 1947 (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Film Shooting Scripts, 1947 (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - "New Mail," 1947 (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - Julliard School Scenario, 1947 (Box 140, Folder 6)
    - Production No. 7 "Big Steel," 1947 (Box 140, Folder 7)
    - Production No. 9 "The Columbian," 1947 (Box 140, Folder 8)
    - Production No. 12 "The New South," 1947 (Box 140, Folder 9)
    - Production No. 13 "Freedom of the Press," 1947 (Box 140, Folder 10)
    - Production No. 50 "This Was America," 1947 (Box 140, Folder 11)
    - Production No. 51 "Germany and the World Today," 1947 (Box 140, Folder 12)
    - Rural Co-op Film, 1947 (Box 140, Folder 13)
  - Air Corps Photos, 1943, (4 Folders) (Box 141, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Air Corps Photos, 1944-1945, (4 Folders) (Box 142, Folder 1 to 4)
- Series VIII: Atomic Power and Nuclear War, 1945-1982
  This series contains files related to films and other work concerned with the issues of nuclear weaponry and atomic warfare.
  - Subseries 1. The Fight For Survival, 1949-1959
    Research, drafts, and correspondence for an article Lorentz wrote for McCall’s in 1957 are contained in these folders.
    - United Nations Radiation Report, 1958 (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - The Fight For Survival Notebooks, 1956-1957, (3 Folders) (Box 143, Folder 2 to 5)
    - Medical Correspondence, 1959 (Box 143, Folder 6)
    - Copyright, 1957 (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Fallout Research, 1949-1959, (3 Folders) (Box 144, Folder 2 to 4)
    - Correspondence and Clippings, 1954-1959, (2 Folders) (Box 144, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Notes and Drafts, 1957, (2 Folders) (Box 144, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Article in McCall’s, 1957 (Box 144, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 2. No Place To Hide, 1945-1950
    Lorentz pictured this as a film about the dangers of the Hydrogen Bomb. “This is a motion picture,” he explained, “that presents in dramatic form everything of importance concerning the atomic bomb and atomic energy that can be told the general public. It is not a scare movie, nor is it a propaganda film.” After years spent trying to find funding, he had to abandon the project. The files contain correspondence, research, and screenplay drafts.
    - Correspondence--Dr. David Bradley, 1948-1950 (Box 145, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence-Harold Young, 1945 (Box 145, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence-Miscellaneous, 1949-1950 (Box 145, Folder 3)
    - Contract--Atomic Energy Committee, 1948 (Box 145, Folder 4)
    - L.E. Brown and Co.--Contracts, 1949 (Box 145, Folder 5)
    - Estimated Production Costs, 1949-1950 (Box 145, Folder 6)
    - Original Outline, 1949-1950 (Box 145, Folder 7)
    - Clippings, 1949 (Box 145, Folder 8)
    - Suggestions, 1949-1950 (Box 145, Folder 9)
    - Final Corrections--Scientists, 1949 (Box 145, Folder 10)
    - Carbons, 1949-1950, (2 Folders) (Box 145, Folder 11 to 12)
    - No Place To Hide, 1949-1950 (Box 145, Folder 13)
    - Drafts, 1949-1950 (Box 145, Folder 14)
    - My Brother’s Keeper, 1949 (Box 145, Folder 15)
    - Atomic Research, 1948-1949 (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - Times Headlines Atomic and Hydrogen Bombs, 1948-1949, (2 Folders) (Box 146, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Atomic Energy, 1948-1949 (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - Bomb Bursts, 1948-1949 (Box 146, Folder 5)
    - D. Bradley--Notes, 1948-1949 (Box 146, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, 1948-1949 (Box 146, Folder 7)
    - William O. Douglas Speeches, 1948-1949, (2 Folders) (Box 146, Folder 8 to 9)
    - E.W. Fager, 1948-1949 (Box 146, Folder 10)
    - Hydrogen Bomb and Miscellaneous, 1948-1949 (Box 146, Folder 11)
    - George C. Marshall, 1948-1949 (Box 146, Folder 12)
    - Men-Research N.P.T.H., 1948-1949 (Box 146, Folder 13)
    - Speeches, 1948-1949 (Box 146, Folder 14)
    - Edward Teller Site B, 1948-1949 (Box 146, Folder 15)
    - Harry Truman, 1949 (Box 146, Folder 16)
    - Bound Copies of Screenplay, 1949-1950, (4 Folders) (Box 147, Folder 1 to 4)
    - No Place to Hide book by David Bradley, 1948 (Box 147, Folder 5)
    - Screenplay Drafts, 1949, (4 Folders) (Box 147, Folder 6 to 9)
    - Clippings, 1949 (Box 147, Folder 10)
    - Atomic Energy Commission Report, 1947-1948 (Box 147, Folder 11)
    - Screenplay Notes, 1949, (2 Folders) (Box 148, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Research, 1949 (Box 148, Folder 3)
    - Loose Papers, 1949 (Box 148, Folder 4)
    - Screenplay Notes, 1949-1951, (3 Folders) (Box 148, Folder 5 to 7)
    - Clippings, 1949 (Box 148, Folder 8)
    - Ninth Copy, 1949 (Box 148, Folder 9)
    - Tenth Copy, 1949 (Box 148, Folder 10)
    - First Draft, 1949 (Box 148, Folder 11)
    - Screenplay Drafts, 1949, (2 Folders) (Box 149, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Treatment, 1949, (2 Folders) (Box 149, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Research Materials, 1949 (Box 149, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 3. Nuclear Energy Research, 1946-1982, undated
    These papers contain correspondence, congressional reports, publications, conference notes, and government studies of nuclear fallout in Hiroshima and Nagisaki.
    - Atomic Bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, 1946 (Box 149, Folder 6)
    - Atoms For Peace, 1957 (Box 150, Folder 1)
    - Ralph Bunche, 1958 (Box 150, Folder 2)
    - Detroit Edison Reactor, 1957 (Box 150, Folder 3)
    - Robley D. Evans, 1948 (Box 150, Folder 4)
    - Leo Goodman (UAW), 1958 (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - International Conference on the Peaceful Use of Atomic Energy, 1951-1955, (2 Folders) (Box 150, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Lorentz Notes, 1950s (Box 150, Folder 8)
    - National Advisory Commission on Radiation, 1959 (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Pacific Gas and Electric, 1969-1970 (Box 150, Folder 10)
    - The Quick and the Dead (NBC), 1950s (Box 150, Folder 11)
    - Radiation: Fact and Controversy, 1962 (Box 150, Folder 12)
    - Radiation: Fact and Controversy, 1962 (Box 151, Folder 1)
    - Radiation Clips and Research, 1958-1962 (Box 151, Folder 2)
    - Radiation on Developing Organisms, 1957 (Box 151, Folder 3)
    - Walter Reuther, 1957 (Box 151, Folder 4)
    - Peace or Pestilience Proofs, 1950s (Box 151, Folder 5)
    - Strauss and Libby Quotes, 1953 (Box 151, Folder 6)
    - UN Scientific Committee on the Effects of Radiation, 1955-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 151, Folder 7 to 8)
    - U.S. Atomic Energy Commission News Releases, 1946 (Box 152, Folder 1)
    - Research Publications, 1947-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 152, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Waste Disposal Hearings, 1959 (Box 152, Folder 4)
    - Windscale Accident, 1957 (Box 152, Folder 5)
    - World Government, 1948 (Box 152, Folder 6)
    - 1958 (Box 152, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 152, Folder 8 to 9)
    - Research, 1955-1956 (Box 152, Folder 10)
    - Research Materials, 1947-1957 (Box 153, Folder 1)
    - Leo Goodman Testimony at Euratom Symposium, 1961 (Box 153, Folder 2)
    - "The PRDC Reactor," 1960s (Box 153, Folder 3)
    - Congressional Testimony, 1950s, (2 Folders) (Box 153, Folder 4 to 5)
    - "Revista Medica," 1964 (Box 153, Folder 6)
    - Research Materials, 1948-1959 (Box 153, Folder 7)
    - Research Materials, 1946-1956 (Box 154, Folder 1)
    - Congressional Hearings, 1957, (2 Folders) (Box 154, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Congressional Hearings, 1959, (3 Folders) (Box 154, Folder 4 to 6)
    - Congressional Hearings, 1959, (2 Folders) (Box 155, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Atomic Energy Commission Publications, 1957, (2 Folders) (Box 155, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Atomic Energy Commission Clippings, 1955-1957, (2 Folders) (Box 155, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Atomic Energy Commission Publications, 1957, (2 Folders) (Box 156, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Atomic Energy Commission Publications, 1958 (Box 157, Folder 1)
    - Fight For Survival Draft, 1950s (Box 157, Folder 2)
    - Nuclear Research, 1956-1971 (Box 157, Folder 3)
    - Second International Conference on the Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy, 1958 (Box 157, Folder 4)
    - Research and Correspondence, 1955-1982 (Box 157, Folder 5)
    - Burlington Conference, 1958 (Box 157, Folder 6)
    - Atomic Energy Accidents, 1957-1958 (Box 157, Folder 7)
    - Leo Goodman Memos, 1963-1971 (Box 158, Folder 1)
    - United World Federalists--Atomic Energy Film, 1947-1951 (Box 158, Folder 2)
    - Fallout, 1955 (Box 158, Folder 3)
    - Research, 1955-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 158, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Radioactive Isotopes in Physiology, 1955 (Box 158, Folder 6)
    - Euratom, 1964 (Box 158, Folder 7)
    - Hazards in the Industrial Environment, 1969-1970 (Box 159, Folder 1)
    - Atomic Research, 1950s (Box 159, Folder 2)
    - Atomic Energy Commission, 1948 (Box 159, Folder 3)
- Series IX: McCall’s, 1935-1941
  Lorentz had a long-running collaboration with the editors at McCall’s, having contributed film reviews to the magazine since the mid-1930s. In 1937, his lyrical essay about the flooding of the Mississippi – a piece of writing that eventually became the narration for The River – initially appeared there as a lead editorial. In the spring of 1941, he helped edit a series of special issues dedicated to questions of national defense. As usual, he was in stride with the needs of the administration in Washington, D.C., which was transitioning from domestic reforms to international preparedness.
  - Subseries 1. General Files, 1941
    This subseries contains expense accounts, reader responses, reprint requests, and correspondence.
    - Complimentary Copies--February-July, 1941, (6 Folders) (Box 160, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Reprint List, 1941 (Box 160, Folder 7)
    - Manuscripts, Unsolicited, 1941 (Box 160, Folder 8)
    - Production Schedules, 1941 (Box 160, Folder 9)
    - Reader Response-- February-July, 1941(5 of 7 Folders) (Box 160, Folder 10 to 14)
    - Reader Response-- February-July, 1941(2 of 7 Folders) (Box 161, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Releases--Photographs, 1941 (Box 161, Folder 3)
    - Requisitions for Supplies, 1941 (Box 161, Folder 4)
    - Requests for Research Materials, 1941 (Box 161, Folder 5)
    - Telegrams, 1941 (Box 161, Folder 6)
    - Expense Accounts, 1941, (22 Folders) (Box 161, Folder 7 to 28)
    - Travel, 1941, (10 Folders) (Box 161, Folder 29 to 38)
    - Individuals, 1941, (21 Folders) (Box 161, Folder 39 to 59)
    - Personnel, 1941, (23 Folders) (Box 162, Folder 1 to 23)
  - Subseries 2. Magazine Articles, 1941
    . Drafts and clippings of articles in McCall’s, mostly related to homefront issues in the lead up to the war, are held in these folders.
    - General, 1941 (Box 162, Folder 24)
    - Daniels--"Home Guard" 1941 (Box 162, Folder 25)
    - Copy--Articles, 1941 (Box 162, Folder 26)
    - Copy--Art Work, 1941 (Box 162, Folder 27)
    - Ideas--National Defense, 1941 (Box 162, Folder 28)
    - Lorentz--"Defense" 1941 (Box 162, Folder 29)
    - Davis--"Women in the War" 1941 (Box 162, Folder 30)
    - Taylor--"Credo Of An American Child" 1941 (Box 162, Folder 31)
    - Daniels, "Boomtown," 1941, (2 Folders) (Box 163, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Captions--"Boomtown," 1941 (Box 163, Folder 3)
    - Nickerson, "Fighting Forces," 1941 (Box 163, Folder 4)
    - Taylor, "Children On Wheels," 1941 (Box 163, Folder 5)
    - Burlingame, "Industrial Story," 1941 (Box 163, Folder 6)
    - Burlingame--"Industrial Story" 1941 (Box 164, Folder 1)
    - Davis--"Women They Left Behind Them" 1941 (Box 164, Folder 2)
    - Captions--"Valley of Steel" 1941 (Box 164, Folder 3)
    - Caldwell--"Flight From the Land" 1941 (Box 164, Folder 4)
    - Bradford--"God in America" 1941 (Box 164, Folder 5)
    - "Children On the Land" 1941 (Box 164, Folder 6)
    - Liebling--"Propaganda Story" 1941 (Box 164, Folder 7)
    - Bemelmans--"Panama" 1941 (Box 165, Folder 1)
    - Langeweische--"Youth in the Air" 1941 (Box 165, Folder 2)
    - Walker--"Youth Training" 1941 (Box 165, Folder 3)
    - Wiese and Taylor--"Youth Conferences 1941 (Box 165, Folder 4)
    - Youth--June, 1941 (Box 165, Folder 5)
    - Winslow--"Sixth Column of Disease" 1941 (Box 165, Folder 6)
    - "Army Questionnaire" 1941 (Box 165, Folder 7)
    - Bemelmans--"The Caribbean" 1941 (Box 165, Folder 8)
    - "A Day in the Life of a Squad" 1941 (Box 165, Folder 9)
    - Lorentz--"The Army and the People" 1941 (Box 165, Folder 10)
    - Nickerson--"Where Do We Go From Here?" 1941 (Box 165, Folder 11)
    - "One Year of Defense" 1941 (Box 165, Folder 12)
    - Reader Letters, 1941 (Box 165, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 3. Research, 1935-1941
    This subseries contains sources and background information for magazine articles.
    - Research Files, 1940-1941, (2 Folders) (Box 165, Folder 14 to 15)
    - Research Files, 1939-1941, (15 Folders) (Box 166, Folder 1 to 15)
    - Research Sources, 1935-1940, (10 Folders) (Box 166, Folder 16 to 25)
    - Research Sources, 1935-1940, (9 Folders) (Box 167, Folder 1 to 9)
  - Subseries 4. Articles by Pare Lorentz, 1936-1941
    This subseries contains copy material from Lorentz’s own journalistic works.
    - Copy Material, 1936-1937, (2 Folders) (Box 167, Folder 10 to 10)
    - Copy Material, 1938-1941, (4 Folders) (Box 168, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Miscellaneous Articles, undated (Box 168, Folder 5)
    - National Defense Section, 1941 (Box 168, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 5. McCall’s Issues and Bound Volumes, 1936-1941
    Volumes of the magazine, flagged occasionally to mark Lorentz’s articles, are contained in this subseries.
    - Bound Volumes, 1936-1937, (3 Folders) (Box 169, Folder 1 to 3)
    - McCall’s Issues, 1941, (7 Folders) (Box 170, Folder 1 to 7)
- Series X: General, 1914-1994, undated
  This series contains other materials, including personal correspondence, files, and records spanning Lorentz’s entire career.
  - Subseries 1. Correspondence, 1914-1990, undated
    . There is some correspondence here between Lorentz and Jogn Steinbeck, as well as material related to Lorentz’s chapter on his relationship with Steinbeck for his autobiography, FDR’s Moviemaker. Letters between Lorentz and Elizabeth Meyer, his second wife, appear here. The Frederic Delano folders contain correspondence between Delano – uncle to the President – and his acquaintances, not with Lorentz himself.
    - John Steinbeck
      - John Steinbeck, 1938-1941 (Box 171, Folder 1)
      - Re: John Steinbeck, 1983-1990 (Box 171, Folder 2)
      - Drafts--"John Steinbeck, A Working Friendship: 1938-1942", undated, (2 Folders) (Box 171, Folder 3 to 4)
      - FDR’s Moviemaker, undated (Box 171, Folder 5)
      - Press Materials For Steinbeck Films, 1950-1952 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Elizabeth Meyer, 1941-1953, undated, (13 Folders) (Box 172, Folder 1 to 13)
    - Frederic A. Delano, 1914-1939
      - New York City--Board of Estimate--Committee on the City Plan Report, 1914 (Box 173, Folder 1)
      - November 1920 (Box 173, Folder 2)
      - 1921 (Box 173, Folder 3)
      - 1922, (8 Folders) (Box 173, Folder 4 to 11)
      - 1923, (8 Folders) (Box 173, Folder 12 to 19)
      - 1924, (7 Folders) (Box 174, Folder 1 to 7)
      - 1925, (10 Folders) (Box 174, Folder 8 to 17)
      - 1926, (6 Folders) (Box 174, Folder 18 to 23)
      - 1927, (9 Folders) (Box 175, Folder 1 to 9)
      - 1928, (10 Folders) (Box 175, Folder 10 to 19)
      - 1929, (9 Folders) (Box 175, Folder 20 to 28)
      - 1930, (8 Folders) (Box 176, Folder 1 to 8)
      - 1931, (5 Folders) (Box 176, Folder 9 to 13)
      - 1932, (4 Folders) (Box 176, Folder 14 to 17)
      - 1933 (Box 176, Folder 18)
      - 1934 (Box 176, Folder 19)
      - 1935-1936 (Box 176, Folder 20)
      - 1939 (Box 176, Folder 21)
  - Subseries 2. KDKA Suit, 1942-1983
    In 1977, Radio Station KDKA in Pittsburgh broadcast an interview with a man who claimed to have been an undercover FBI-agent during the New Deal. This agent, who referred to himself as “Dominic,” named Lorentz as a Communist. Lorentz sued the station. During the trial it was revealed that “Dominic” was in fact Joseph Mazzei, a man with a “criminal record” and a history of perjury, whom the U.S. Supreme Court had already diagnosed with a “pathological condition.” Westinghouse, KDKA’s parent company sent Lorentz a check for $25,000 and a written apology, acknowledging “the distinguished list of your lifetime accomplishments which clearly demonstrates your outstanding record as an American citizen.” Contains trial transcripts, court records, and correspondence.
    - Trial Materials, 1953-1978 (Box 177, Folder 1)
    - Legal Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 177, Folder 2)
    - KDKA Legal, 1977-1979 (Box 177, Folder 3)
    - KDKA Pittsburgh, 1977-1979 (Box 177, Folder 4)
    - Misc. Notes Re: KDKA, 1977-1979 (Box 177, Folder 5)
    - Background, 1977-1979, (2 Folders) (Box 177, Folder 6 to 7)
    - William Donovan, 1977-1979 (Box 177, Folder 8)
    - Credits, 1977-1979 (Box 177, Folder 9)
    - Notes Regarding Article, 1977-1979 (Box 177, Folder 10)
    - Expenses, 1977-1979 (Box 177, Folder 11)
    - KDKA--Money, 1977-1979 (Box 177, Folder 12)
    - Rose Schmidt Dixon Hasley and White, 1977-1979 (Box 177, Folder 13)
    - Court Dismissal Documents, 1977-1979 (Box 177, Folder 14)
    - Personal Letters, 1977-1979 (Box 177, Folder 15)
    - KDKA, 1977-1979 (Box 177, Folder 16)
    - RKO Law Suit, 1941-1948 (Box 177, Folder 17)
    - KDKA, 1977-1979 (Box 177, Folder 18)
    - Trial Documents, 1979 (Box 178, Folder 1)
    - Pare Lorentz Affidavit, 1979 (Box 178, Folder 2)
    - Pare Lorentz Deposition, 1978, (2 Folders) (Box 178, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Kennedy Webster and Gardner, 1977-1983 (Box 178, Folder 5)
    - Radio Show Transcript, 1977-1978 (Box 178, Folder 6)
    - Transcript of Show, 1977 (Box 179, Folder 1)
    - Motion for Summary Judgment, 1978 (Box 179, Folder 2)
    - PL Affidavit, 1978 (Box 179, Folder 3)
    - FBI Report, 1977-1979 (Box 179, Folder 4)
    - Supreme Court Decision, 1956 (Box 179, Folder 5)
    - Pre-Trial Narrative, 1978 (Box 179, Folder 6)
    - Plaintiff’s Rebuttal, 1979 (Box 179, Folder 7)
    - Law Suit RKO, 1942-1947, (3 Folders) (Box 179, Folder 8 to 10)
  - Subseries 3. Conferences--Ceremonies--Presentations, 1944-1994
    This subseries contains papers and correspondence related to various public events, including “The Conference that Never Was Held.” A planned international summit to discuss global issues that was cancelled after President Roosevelt died. Fifty years later it finally occurred as the Rio conference.
    - Suffield Connecticut Writers Conference, 1972 (Box 180, Folder 1)
    - Point Four Program and Conference, 1948-1952
      - Correspondence, 1948-1951 (Box 180, Folder 2)
      - Conference Meeting, 1952 (Box 180, Folder 3)
      - Conference Publications, 1952 (Box 180, Folder 4)
      - Conference Notes, 1952 (Box 180, Folder 5)
    - The Conference that Never was Held, 1944-1994
      - Correspondence and Research, 1944-1994 (1 of 4 Folders) (Box 180, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence and Research, 1944-1994 (3 of 4 Folders) (Box 181, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Correspondence with Adlai Stevension, 1957, (2 Folders) (Box 181, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Speech Notes, 1972 (Box 181, Folder 6)
    - Presentation at University of Wisconsin-Oshkosh, 1971 (Box 181, Folder 7)
    - Dedication of Pare Lorentz Room at University of Wisconsin-Oshkosh, 1974 (Box 181, Folder 8)
    - Department of Agriculture AWARD, 1963 (Box 181, Folder 9)
    - West Virginia Wesleyan, 1972 (Box 182, Folder 1)
    - American School England, 1960 (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 4. Writings about Pare Lorentz, 1965-1979